<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nomad Blog</title>
    <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nomad Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 16:58:16 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nomadblog.de/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/neural-networks-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 16:58:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/neural-networks-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs) are the hype in Computer Science, and I have jumped on the bandwagon. I will surely write about how I want to apply ANNs to the field of communication networks in some later post, but for now I want to present what I have gathered about these lovely little thingies, and show it in a way that would have been very useful to me when I first started looking into ANNs:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Madrid &#43; Portugal</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/travel-stories/madrid-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 21:53:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/travel-stories/madrid-2019/</guid>
      <description>A short travel story of a visit to Madrid and a 100km hike from Porto, Portugal to the border spain along the Camino Portugues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 20:43:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/investing/</guid>
      <description>A conclusion on how I could invest the money I save to fight inflation and possibly grow it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 22:35:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/budget/</guid>
      <description>How do you acquire the moneyz?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plan</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/theplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 22:17:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/theplan/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s this about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clion Libraries</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/clion-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 15:56:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/clion-libraries/</guid>
      <description>How to link a static library project in CLion to a unittest executable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OMNeT&#43;&#43; and INET Simulator Setup</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnet-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 10:51:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnet-setup/</guid>
      <description>Installing the simulator + INET framework on Arch Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AUR package with invalid MD5Checksum</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/makepkg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 10:28:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/makepkg/</guid>
      <description>I had an annoying problem: for the simulator I use for research I needed a specific library, as the simulator uses it.
This specific library osgearth is available in the Arch Linux&amp;rsquo;s AUR, but the package maintainer put a wrong MD5 Checksum into the PKGBUILD. Let&amp;rsquo;s say we trust the maintainer and don&amp;rsquo;t believe someone tinkered with the files. What do you do?
Go to an arbitrary directory
cd ~/Download mkdir osgearth cd osgearth  Download the Snapshot from the AUR which should contain the PKGBUILD; extract it from the archive file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling a display based on a PIR motion detector</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/raspi-pir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 15:09:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/raspi-pir/</guid>
      <description>How to turn a display on and off based on an infrared motion detector (PIR) using Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation evaluation in OMNeT&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnetpp-sim-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 16:57:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnetpp-sim-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>OMNeT++ network simulator allows for extensive and modular simulation of network scenarios. When simulation concept, implementation, configuration and running are said and done, the evaluation is the next step. Some built-in functionalities of the IDE allow for an idea on how the network performed. This was cumbersone for me personally, and I prefer to evaluate the numerical scalar result values in MATLAB anyway.
When you run a large number of simulations, then you don&amp;rsquo;t want to open each file in the IDE, select the relevant entries and export them to a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing D2D mode selection in OMNeT&#43;&#43;/SIMUlte</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnetpp-d2d-mode-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 16:41:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnetpp-d2d-mode-selection/</guid>
      <description>Device2Device (D2D) Mode Selection is the process of deciding whether a user device should communicate directly (D2D Mode) or via the eNodeB base station (Infrastructure Mode). A number of metrics can be taken into account for this decision, such as the interference generated that will affect other devices or the expected datarate of each mode. Once a researcher has come up with an idea, they will want to evaluate it. Using the OMNeT++ network simulator as a starting point, and adding the SIMUlte framework on top enables one to simulate LTE networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an LTE resource scheduler in OMNeT&#43;&#43;/SIMUlte</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnetpp-scheduler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 15:59:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnetpp-scheduler/</guid>
      <description>SIMUlte is an extension framework for the network simulator OMNeT++. It enables simulations of LTE telecommunications.
In this context, resource scheduling is the problem of allocating transmission resources residing in the dimensions of time and of frequency band to user devices. A resource block can be depicted like this:
There are a number of optimization targets we would like to meet:
 system throughput: we want to push out as much data as possible fairness: we want all devices to be able to push out data power efficiency: we want to use as little power as possible  So in the end, resource scheduling boils down to a complex optimization problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to safely SSH into your own computer</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/safe-ssh-to-own-computer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 20:01:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/safe-ssh-to-own-computer/</guid>
      <description>Allowing incoming SSH connections to your personal computer is something you want to avoid. If you have to do it, then do it in a safe way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading module and simulation parameters in OMNeT&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnetpp-reading-parameters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 16:43:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/omnetpp-reading-parameters/</guid>
      <description>How to access general simulation parameters at runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding equidistant points on a circle</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/equidistant-points-on-circle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 11:34:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/equidistant-points-on-circle/</guid>
      <description>How to find the positions of a number of equidistant points on a circle, including C++ code to do it for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lexicographical index calculation</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/lexicographical-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 14:21:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/lexicographical-index/</guid>
      <description>Finding the index in a container that holds the frequency of elements in lexicographical order. Includes C++ source code for word frequency vectors (that makes use of this index calculation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word frequency vectors and their uses</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/word-frequency-vectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 18:45:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/word-frequency-vectors/</guid>
      <description>Word frequency vectors applied on evolutionary distances between DNA sequences and on bit error rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-domain nginx configuration</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 20:21:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/nerdy/nginx/</guid>
      <description>How to configure nginx to serve two different HTML directories to two different domains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>