<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Planning on Nomad Blog</title>
    <link>http://nomadblog.de/tags/planning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Planning on Nomad Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 20:43:57 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://nomadblog.de/tags/planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing</title>
      <link>http://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 20:43:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/investing/</guid>
      <description>I was recently approached by a financial advisor of sorts. Having just set up my first savings plan, I asked myself how I could invest the money I save. To be honest: I had no idea on this topic.
Well, in a first meeting I had explained my situation to the advisor lady: I want to save about 20.000Eur within the next four years, and when I do invest it, it has to be in sustainable, green projects and businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget</title>
      <link>http://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 22:35:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/budget/</guid>
      <description>How the heck do you save 20k (where does this figure come from?)? You make a plan&amp;hellip; I guess.
I work as a research assistant at a German university, my goal is to write a dissertation, get a PhD, and then I&amp;rsquo;m off. This has some advantages, as a) it pays quite well and b) it has an endpoint. In my case there is no fixed deadline, I am done when I am done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plan</title>
      <link>http://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/theplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 22:17:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/theplan/</guid>
      <description>The idea&amp;rsquo;s quite simple.
 Save money. Buy a used car &amp;ndash; preferably a 4-wheel-drive. Equip that car with a bed and things you need when you live in a car. Learn how to repair said car. Go drive east until you can&amp;rsquo;t.  And meanwhile, write about it. Why? Mostly because I want to. I like reading other people&amp;rsquo;s blogs, I like to be able to keep all friends and family up-to-date, and just maybe someone likes what I do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>