<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nomad Blog</title>
    <link>https://nomadblog.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nomad Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 13:54:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nomadblog.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/about/seba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 13:54:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/about/seba/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Sebastian. I live in the beautiful port city of Hamburg, in northern Germany.
I am a research assistant by trade, and write about this life over at syntaxsugar.de.
I have come to love the traveler&amp;rsquo;s life when I did my first big trip at 19 when I went to Australia for a travel &amp;amp; work stay of 9 months. We would work and save money for a car, then drive that car some several thousand kilometers south and enjoy every moment of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 20:43:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/investing/</guid>
      <description>I was recently approached by a financial advisor of sorts. Having just set up my first savings plan, I asked myself how I could invest the money I save. To be honest: I had no idea on this topic.
Well, in a first meeting I had explained my situation to the advisor lady: I want to save about 20.000Eur within the next four years, and when I do invest it, it has to be in sustainable, green projects and businesses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Budget</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 22:35:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/budget/</guid>
      <description>How the heck do you save 20k (where does this figure come from?)? You make a plan&amp;hellip; I guess.
I work as a research assistant at a German university, my goal is to write a dissertation, get a PhD, and then I&amp;rsquo;m off. This has some advantages, as a) it pays quite well and b) it has an endpoint. In my case there is no fixed deadline, I am done when I am done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plan</title>
      <link>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/theplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 22:17:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nomadblog.de/posts/planning/theplan/</guid>
      <description>Alright, so here I am. Sitting in my flat in Hamburg. What should one do with life? There&amp;rsquo;s so many fascinating things to do, but one of them seems to beat all others: travel!
For uncountably many years (okay, not that many, but quite a few) I have known that travelling is one of my most favourite pastimes. I have done a few trips, from three-week excursions to China to nine-month travel-and-work trips to Australia, and each and every time I came to love the freedom that travelling brings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>